KATIE ANILIONIS

MERCHANDISING AND OPERATIONS PROFESSIONAL

PROFILE

A dedicated professional with 10+ years of work experience in merchandising, retail and showroom management, sales, operations, production and product development. Currently enrolled in the University of Denver Coding Boot Camp, with a completion date of December 2020.

CONTACT

 \smile

Kanilionis@gmail.com



720.289.9249



4225 E. Iliff Ave. Denver, CO 80222



https://www.linkedin.com/in/katie-anilionis-4720258a/



github.com/kanilionis

EDUCATION

B.A. in Communication

w/French minor

University of Tampa, 2008

Certificate in Web Development

University of Denver, 2020

SKILLS

Brand Management

Vendor Relations

Microsoft Office

SAP

PowerBI

HTML

JavaScript

AJAX, API

CSS

Attention to Detail

Social Perceptiveness

Critical Thinking

Judgment and Decision Making

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Category Manager, September 2018-March 2020

eBags | Greenwood Village, CO

- Head merchant for 3rd party luggage and travel accessories, as well as eBags Brand and HOB travel accessories.
- Managed pricing, assortment, promotions, and site placements to improve sales and margin, leading to sales growth above company-wide expectations.
- Analyzed selling report and OLAPs to find new strategies and opportunities to increase sales volume and conversion rates.

Merchandise Operations Associate, January 2018-September 2018 eBags | Greenwood Village, CO

- Immediately starting working with merchandisers and photography teams to get product live on the site.
- Managed SKU changes and issues with missing color codes in Admin3, and managed buildsheet and image submissions.
- Proficient in workflow processes, in-house systems including the BI Portal, Admin2, Admin3, and JIRA.

Office Manager/Bookkeeper, December 2016-January 2018

A Line Boutique | Denver, CO

- Managed all office procedures and policies as well as finances, bookkeeping and human resources.
- Oversaw Quickbooks: integration with Springboard Retail, reconciled invoices, monitored cash flow and categorized all charges.
- Formed relationships with vendors to effectively pay invoices as well as confirm or negotiate discounts and payment terms.
- HR duties, including on-boarding process, paperwork, training, and tracking hours/PTO.

Account Executive, Production and Showroom Assistant, August 2011-November 2011, August 2013-August 2016

Parker | New York, NY

- Boosted sales by adding over 100 accounts for Parker and Parker Black (including various department stores, specialty stores and online accounts).
- Worked very closely with designers to create balanced, and well-merchandised collections, and was involved in all steps of creating Parker Black Collection.
- Analyzed weekly selling reports to understand best and worst sellers, applied information to help with planning and designing future collections.
- Created names for colors, prints and garments for each season, coordinated fittings
 with production team, patternmakers and designers, tracked development of fabrics
 and samples from India and China, and uploaded pricing, vendor and fabric
 information, and photos into AMT and NuOrder.

East Coast Account Executive, November 2011-August 2013

Glamhouse | New York, NY

- Merchandised jewelry with great visual representation of all collections.
- Sold merchandise to buyers during trade shows and showroom appointments.
- Solely represented three women's contemporary jewelry lines for the East Coast and worked with online and brick and mortar major stores such as ShopBop, Bloomingdale's, and Lord & Taylor.
- Increased total sales more than 30% YoY, and achieved and maintained top salesperson position companywide.